A Finding Aid to the Raymond and Margaret Horowitz Papers, 1903-2007, bulk 1960-2007, in the Archives of American Art AAA.hororaym
Archives of American Art
- Artwork, Sold, or Donated, 1903; 1950-2003; Series 2; 2 Linear feet Boxes 3-5
  - Sargent, John Singer – Portrait of Mme. Paul Helleu, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Sargent, John Singer – Venetian Canal Scene, 1963-1965 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Shields, Thomas, Park Siesta, undated; 1962-1985 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Sloan, John – Waiting, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Sloan, John – Savings Bank, 1971-1987; undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Smith, Hopkinson F. – Venice, undated; 1984 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Smith, Hopkinson F. – Boating On The Thames, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Sterner, Albert – Maude and Marie, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Sterner, Albert – Seated Figure, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Stewart, Julius F. – Portrait Of A Lady, 1979-1984 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Sully, Thomas – Portrait Sketch, 1963-1965 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Tarbell, Edmund C. – Woman In Pink and Green, 1966-1996; undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Thayer, Abbott Handerson – Roses, 1978-1992 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Twachtman, John H. – Main Street, Gloucester, 1961-1966; 1903 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Twachtman, John H. – Cascade (Pastel), 1960-1966; undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Twachtman, John H. – Bickford’s Float, undated; 1962-1987 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Twachtman, John H. – Cascade (Oil), 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Twachtman, John H. – Street Scene, undated; 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Twachtman, John H. – Niagara Falls, undated; 1964-1996 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Twachtman, John H. – Farmhouse and Lilacs, 1966-1989 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Twachtman, John H. – The Boat Yard, undated; 1977-1983 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Twachtman, John H. – The Dock Bridgeport, undated; 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Twachtman, John H. – Winter, Avondale, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Walkowitz, Abraham - Paris, 1961-1980 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Weir, John Alden - The Water Gate, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Weir, John Alden - On The Thames, 1962-1980 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Wiles, Irving R. - Berceuse, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Wiles, Irving R. – The Girl From Martinique, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Young, Mahonri M. – Mother and Child, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Miscellaneous Paintings, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Accession Records, 1959-circa 1994; Series 3; 0.4 Linear feet Box 5
  Records provide documentation of the paintings and prints represented in the Raymond and Margaret Horowitz collection. Included are scattered materials relating to purchases, costs, and an insurance appraisal.
  The materials generally include letters of understanding; appraisals; and information on purchases and sales, exhibition history, and published references. Invoices of artwork (photocopies) document the Horowitzes' interests in various artists, whose work formed the basis of their core collection.
  Files are arranged in alphabetical order, by artist's surname.
  - Paintings
    - Inventory of Paintings, By Artist, A-W, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Anshutz, Thomas – Bunker, Dennis Miller, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Chase, William Merritt – Dewing, Thomas, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Fisher, Mark – Myers, Jerome, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Potthast, Edward H. – Robinson, Theodore, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Sargent, John Singer – Weir, John Alden, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Prints
    - Inventory List of Prints, B-W, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Bellows, George – Benson, Frank, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Cassatt, Mary – Henri, Robert, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Sterne, Maurice – Whistler, James McNeil, circa 1994 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Purchases, Paintings, Drawings, and Prints, 1959-circa 1963 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Cost and Fair Market Value of Paintings, circa 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Insurance Appraisal, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Invoices for Artwork, Artists, A-Y, 1960-1965 (Box 5, Folder 60-61)
- Catalog Information, circa 1960-1967; Series 4; 3 Folders Box 5
  This series consists of catalog information sheets documenting works of art acquired from circa 1960-1967. Records provide descriptive information, e.g., title, media, date of execution, source and date of purchase, published sources, provenance, and exhibition history.
  The files are maintained in their original order and are arranged alphabetically, by artist's surname.
  - By Artist, B-W, circa 1960 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - By Artist, A-Y, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 63-64)